<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terminal</title>
    <link>https://cmclcas.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 19:00:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cmclcas.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Germfree Adolescents</title>
      <link>https://cmclcas.github.io/posts/germfreeadolescents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 19:00:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmclcas.github.io/posts/germfreeadolescents/</guid>
      <description>So, I want to start a music blog. Here it is!
I&amp;rsquo;ll start with a little introduction, I&amp;rsquo;m a college radio DJ in the Boston area, and I love punk and post-punk music. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to know much more than that, honestly. I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to this sort of stuff for years, and one of my recent goals has been to delve deeper into the history of the artists and the albums and the record labels that I&amp;rsquo;ve really enjoyed.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;So, I want to start a music blog.  Here it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll start with a little introduction, I&amp;rsquo;m a college radio DJ in the Boston area, and I love punk and post-punk music.  You don&amp;rsquo;t need to know much more than that, honestly.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to this sort of stuff for years, and one of my recent goals has been to delve deeper into the history of the artists and the albums and the record labels that I&amp;rsquo;ve really enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real question is how to start such a thing.  Do you start with a random album?  An album that means a lot to you?  One of the first albums that you listened to?  I&amp;rsquo;ve been mulling this over for a while.  Picking a random album could be easy - I tried to start a blog last summer as well, using the randomizer from 1001albumsgenerator.  But that fizzled after I realized that I hate limiting myself to one album from that book a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about albums that mean a lot to me - but that&amp;rsquo;s just so hard to pick one.  I mean.  Try picking just one album, out of the many that you resonate with to be that Number One.  It&amp;rsquo;s hard, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First album though.  That&amp;rsquo;s a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first punk album I ever listened to in its entirety was Germfree Adolescents by X-Ray Spex.  And it&amp;rsquo;s still one of my favorite albums of all time.  Sorry, I lied there - this is both the first album, and one of the more meaningful ones.  Don&amp;rsquo;t hold it against me, okay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways.  The reason that I first listened to Germfree Adolescents was because I was a band kid in high school.  Deeply embarrassing, right?  Nah.  The only embarrassing part was that I was a saxophonist.  An alto saxophonist.  Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;m better now (I switched to clarinet).  But that&amp;rsquo;s why I picked up Germfree Adolescents.  I was a deeply uncool band kid, with a chip on their shoulder about it all.  I wanted to be punk rock.  I wanted to listen to heavy music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And somehow, my first instinct was to search up &amp;ldquo;punk rock with saxophone&amp;rdquo;.  I wanted to find punk I could play - I had nothing with a string save for an upright piano in my parent&amp;rsquo;s living room.  So it had to be punk with a saxophone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fell in love with the album, and with the saxophone playing of who I thought was Lora Logic (turns out, as I learned later, it was Rudi Thomson).  And I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get enough of Poly Styrene&amp;rsquo;s vocals.  It broke my heart to hear that they only released one record.  But this was enough to take my punk rocker dreams from just an aspiration to be &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo; to an actual appreciation for the genre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the album though, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first song, Art-I-Ficial, has such a fun opening guitar riff that really hooked me as a kid, and still hits now.  Not much else to say about the track, sorry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obsessed with You is one of my favorites from this album.  Poly Styrene&amp;rsquo;s voice has such a shrill quality on it and it&amp;rsquo;s so interesting to hear.  I really appreciate how raw her voice sounds at times even on album recordings.  That&amp;rsquo;s something I appreciate about the recording quality of this era of British punk bands, a choice to leave a little bit of the polish off the final track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t very much like Warrior in Woolworths.  It&amp;rsquo;s repetitive, and it feels weird for it to sit between two killer tracks as it does.  One of the weaker songs, and I&amp;rsquo;m also not a fan of the saxophone on the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Let&amp;rsquo;s Submerge rips.  I love this track so much!  Every part of this song works for me.  Especially the saxophone on this track.  Plus, I&amp;rsquo;m always a fan of &amp;ldquo;spooky&amp;rdquo; lyrics.  It&amp;rsquo;s not really proto-goth in any of the other elements, but the picture the lyrics paint could be.  Maybe?  Either way, it rips.  Great track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bass on I Can&amp;rsquo;t Do Anything is one of the reasons I wanted to get into punk bass back when I was in high school.  I loved how it played with the saxophone in the opening, and I still do.  Now that I actually own a bass, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to learn some of this track.  Again, killer vocals.  Not sure why, but the chorus with &amp;ldquo;Freddy tried to strangle me / With my plastic popper beads / But I hit him back / With my pet rat&amp;rdquo; gets stuck in my head all the time.  What it means, I&amp;rsquo;ll never know.  I don&amp;rsquo;t want to know.  Love it to bits though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identity is one of those songs that really spoke to me when I was younger.  The lyrics are great, and I think Poly Styrene&amp;rsquo;s performance of them are fantastic.  It still holds up today as much as it did to me in high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first song on the B side, Genetic Engineering, has some great sax licks on it.  As well as some great vocals, once again.  I sound like a broken record.  But it&amp;rsquo;s true!  There&amp;rsquo;s a reason I picked this as the first album I&amp;rsquo;d write about here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again.  The saxophone.  It&amp;rsquo;s so good on I Live Off You.  I&amp;rsquo;m not in love with the rest of the track, but the saxophone on it is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about the guitar.  Shocking!  Anyways, the opening riff of I Am A Poseur is ironed into my brain.  This whole track is just great.  I absolutely love the rhythmic saxophone bleats in the middle.  Again, something that stuck with me, lyrically, in high school a ton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another song I&amp;rsquo;m a little less in love with, the title track Germ Free Adolescents, is fine.  It&amp;rsquo;s a little slow for me, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s just weaker than most everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that the next song is Plastic Bag.  The speed up into the song really highlights how slow and dragging Germ Free Adolescents is.  Granted, this song then slows down a good bit in it&amp;rsquo;s own right.  It&amp;rsquo;s also quite cheesy.  I do enjoy the chorus though, the rest of the song is just.  Less great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the last song The World Turned Dayglo saves the day.  What a SONG!  The saxophone all over the track is slick, and Poly Styrene&amp;rsquo;s vocals are piercing in the best possible way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a glaring omission here though.  This album originally didn&amp;rsquo;t include the other singles that X-Ray Spex released, but they were added in repressings as far as I know.  I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into all of their singles, just the one you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering about.  The rest are all great but they&amp;rsquo;ve got nothing on the first track I ever heard of by X-Ray Spex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh Bondage Up Yours! is one of the best punk singles ever recorded, in my opinion.  Honestly, I think you could argue for it being the best.  Everything works.  From the intro (&amp;ldquo;Some people think little girls should be seen and not heard, but I think&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;) is the perfect hook.  The saxophone is harsh.  Poly Styrene screams her ass off.  It&amp;rsquo;s perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was attending a local club, and at around 1:58 AM the DJ dropped this track.  Last track of the night.  I had been dancing with friends on and off since around 10:45 or so.  My whole body was tired.  But it was like I was fucking posessed.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been more excited to hear the intro, or danced as hard in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X-Ray Spex changed my life by getting me into punk rock.  And the tracks they recorded still give me heart attacks on the dance floor almost a decade after I first heard them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
